HEBER BERMUDEZ

Statistician

hebermudezg@unal.edu.co · (+57)3115604078 www.linkedin.com/in/hebermudezg

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I am an Statistician with experience collecting, analyzing, interpreting, and presenting quantitative information, providing insight and recommendations on policies and strategies. I work in data visualization for business intelligence, data mining, written reports, development and implementation of predictive models, database management and software development. I possess strong IT and analytical skills, as well as the interpersonal and communication skills to share findings with colleagues and clients. I apply statistical theories and methods to solve practical problems in a range of sectors, including; business, engineering, science, education, the environment, finance, government, health, market research, transportation, software companies, among others.

EDUCATION

National University of Colombia

2015-2021

Undergraduate in Statistics. Overall GPA: 4.1/5.0

SENA 2013-2015

Technologist in industrial production managemen.

SENA 2010-2012

Software development technician.

EXPERIENCE

Infection and Cancer Research Group

Dec 2020 - Jul 2021

Epidemiological data analysis, Antioquia University.

• I provided support from my knowledge and experience in the statistical analysis of epidemiological data for research projects and publications in scientific journals, achieving the identification of risk profiles of breast cancer in Latin American women considering hormonal and reproductive factors.

Unalytics, data science seedbed

Jan 2019 - Jun 2020

Assistant student, National University of Colombia.

• I directed the seedbed and taught theoretical and practical skills in the area of data science, data analysis and artificial intelligence, where I managed together with my team to develop various products and exhibit them in competitions, conferences and colloquia. See more: https://unalyticsteam.github.io/unalytics/

Biosuplies SAS Jan 2014 - Feb 2015

Documentation and quality control assistant, Biosuplies SAS

- I created forms and process manuals as well as software programs to automate administrative tasks such as inventory maintenance and quality control.
- I created a form to reduce the times of prescription of magisterial medicines.

AWARDS AND RECOGNITIONS

Student Representative (2019)

Student representative of the Conflict Resolution and Disciplinary Aspects Committee of the Faculty of Sciences of the National University of Colombia elected by vote.

Founder of Unalytics - data science seedbed (2019)

Founder of the analytical and data science seedbed attached to the school of statistics of the National University of Colombia as a pedagogical strategy.

Best degree project (2011)

Technical College of the City of Ibagué (Highschool) - Best degree project related to software programming and website design.

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Programming R, Python, Java, Visual Basic, React Native. **Databases** SQL. Data Visualization, Bussines Intelligence Power BI, Tableau. Machine Learning and Artificial intelligence Pandas, Numpy, Tensorflow, Scikit-learn, Tidyverse, Knime Wireframe Microsoft Powerpoint, Keynote, Microsoft Excel. Visual Design Photoshop, Ilustrator, Premier Pro, After Efects. Website design HTML and CSS. **Typesetting Document** Latex.

ACADEMIC ACTIVITIES	
XIII National statistics colloquium Attendant, National University of Colombia.	2021
XII National statistics colloquium Sepaker: Machine learning for text analysis, National University of Colombia.	2019
XXIX International statistical symposium Speaker: Text mining to study some terminologies about data science in Colombia, Northern University.	2019
DATATON BC Data science and artificial intelligence challenge, Bancolombia bank. Estimation of personal expenses. We were top 60% Kaggle Challenge	2020
DATATON BC Data science and artificial intelligence challenge, Bancolombia bank. Modeling of credit risk from the digital trace. We were top 20% Kaggle Challenge	2019
DATATON BC Data science and artificial intelligence challenge, Bancolombia bank. Text mining for expense identification. We were selected from the top 10 groups of 60	2018

CERTIFICATIONS, MOOCS

Introduction to data science

Coursera, Autonomous University of Mexico

Deep learning

Coursera, Deeplearning.ai

SQL for Data science

 $Coursera,\ DAVIS\ University$

LANGUAGES

English Intermediate

Spanish Native.